on today's video we are going to talk
about ice cream recipe books which ones
you should try if you're a beginner and
which ones to
[Music]
avoid I've had tons of ice cream recipe
books over the years and some are much
better than others especially if you're
looking at it from a scientific point of
view if you're looking at it from just
you want some recipes you don't care
whether they're good or not then you
know just go to Amazon and type in ice
cream recipe book and you will see
hundreds of absolute rubbish so if you
followed this channel for a while I
hundreds of recipes on here for from
ones back in the UK that use full-on
fatty double cream to single cream to
half and half
to Canadian whipping cream everything in
between um vegan non vegan fatty fat fat
and sugarfree keto protein all all of
them now it's taken me years to to
really learn how to make ice cream well
and it's it's not really super difficult
I'm not doing anything groundbreaking
all I've done is over the years learned
what ingredients are important and what
they do within the actual recipe itself
so let's start with one recipe book that
most people that like ice cream we've
probably seen and that is this one Ben
and
Jerry's ice cream and dessert book um
this this is
[__] this is one of the worst ice cream
recipe books out there from Ben and
Jerry's too you know probably the
biggest name in ice cream in the world
but why is this so bad it's bad because
they use a standard base that you then
modify with a couple of ingredients so
it it tells you about Theory but
actually doesn't tell you anything about
Theory at all it's just words and then
after it explains the theory it tells
you the three different bases where they
use light cream and condensed milk which
doesn't make wonderful ice cream
condensed milk is it's almost like a
cheats ice cream it has a really weird
flavor compared to Natural churned Ice
Cream it's functional and it will get
out of a pinch you can I've done
condensed milk recipes on here and they
taste you know great because I've
modified the recipes to soup but you're
not going to get the epitome of
perfection by using condensed milk in
your ice cream and it kind of just goes
on down down this rout everything's got
eggs in because you know that that's
super boring and oldfashioned and even
when you make some of their recipes
they're nothing like the tubs that you
would buy to be fair the tubs now are
nothing like you used to buy
20 years ago but that one I would just
avoid if you're making ice cream with
kids that one actually is quite good cuz
it's really simple regardless of whether
the recipes are any good not if you want
to improve so the next is the perfect
scoop David liebovitz this is an
excellent book if you want to learn
about the science of ice cream and the
recipes are predominantly very good this
recipe book is for you there's another
recipe book as well which I'm going to
strongly recommend but this is strongly
recommended ice cream recipe book number
one it's really well L out the book is
really high quality the recipes are
excellent and you know it the science
isn't super in-depth in here but the
recipes use a scientific base to create
them so that is an excellent book if you
don't have it add it to your collection
the next one is the van Luan recipe book
Artisan ice cream it's actually a really
nice kind of you know textured book I I
like this one it's um it's a good size
got great pictures in there the recipes
are pretty decent to be fair you know
they're not a groundbreaking but they
they are good and they've got some
really unusual ones like black sesame
ice cream in here it's a vanilla base
but you know that aside you know you got
your basic standard stuff rhubarb
crumble ice cream it's got some really
nice pictures in here but they do have a
tendency to go over the top with some
ingredients like coconut and cashew the
vegan recipes in here all use a cashew
base which is a pain in the a-hole to
actually make here there are much easier
ways to do plant-based recipes but this
has got a good selection of plant-based
ice cream in so if that's your bag this
recipe book is a really really nice one
love that it's got the reflective kind
of writing on the front if you are into
the science of ice cream this won't help
you much but it has got some decent
recipes in so that's another book to
try if you are in the
UK this recip book is a fun one to have
Judes if you don't live in the UK Judes
is a national ice cream company and they
have come on Leaps and Bounds actually
over the years they were quite Bland and
boring but then they started to create
some really really nice ice creams uh
you could buy them in you you still can
buy them in UK supermarkets I used to
get mine from sabes in calcot near
Reading um yeah the the recipes in
here they are you know it's kind of
mixed you've got swirl lollies a lolly
in the UK is a popsicle in North America
I find Lolly a much more fun happy word
than popsicle but po popsicle I don't
know it's got a nice ring to it popsicle
Lolly you got some uh some more
lollies sound very British when I say
lollies um some of the recipes are a bit
funky uh and that's because they use you
know the bloody cashew base which is
fine but again much better ways they and
I find that a lot of these come out way
too hard in the they come out the
freezer way too hard so you need to warm
them up for 75 years before you can eat
them and I don't know whether it's just
me but I really really hate seeing
people
online do
this don't put ice cream in a loaf tin
you you're you're going to ruin your
[__] loaf tin don't be a bell end
that's for making bread not for putting
ice cream in it's a Modern Trend that I
really hate
so this book is
okay if you have got nothing else to
spend your money on but there are much
much better ones out there the next book
is salt and straws ice cream cookbook
I'm going to put a picture on the screen
here this book is really good I have it
digitally so it's on my laptop it's got
some really nice recipes in there it's
some fun recipes and salt and straw got
history doing some really unique flavors
especially around certain holidays like
Thanksgiving you know turkey and CR and
all this kind of stuff so it's a fun one
to try the recipes actually are decent
so don't be afraid of spending money on
that one whether you get the physical
copy or the digital copy both would be
worth it I had the physical copy it
didn't make it over in the move during
the fire so I have the digital copy now
but really nice inspiration a plenty in
that recipe book so that one is
recommended the next book is this one
hello my name is ice cream By Dana cre
this one is possibly the number one
recipe book if you want to understand
science behind ice cream a bit more it's
an excellent book and it's really well
explained it doesn't go too much into
wordiness it's not too wordy it's got
some great illustration the recipes are
easy to follow and there's a really
really good selection of recipes on
there so so the last one that I'm going
to talk about is ample Hills they've
actually got a few recipe books out
there and this one is just Flatout ample
Hills creamy though this is long before
the original owners got the boot which
is super sad because ultimately ample
Hills has gone downhill since doing that
and the original owners are the nicest
people in the world and they I think
they are again now making some ice cream
some good flavors but it's one of those
situations that is political and I'm not
getting involved in politics on this
channel because I make ice cream but
it's got some really nice flavors in
there the ice creams come out really
really nicely and some of the flavors
are quite unique broad selection between
fruit-based Dairy based and everything
else so give that one a try apart from
the Ben &
Jerry's recipe book The possibly worst
recipe book for a home ice cream maker
is gelato MSA the recipes now before my
American followers get up in arms
because you know when I did the
comparison I had serious hate from my
Aussie crew it's not that I don't like
gelato MSA because the company is
excellent and the work that Nick put
into that business is Second To None the
recipes are great we have great
interaction between themselves and me on
social media it is purely the fact that
that recipe book which is here was not
actually designed for home users even
though in the book it states for home
users the recipes are no good for you
making at home you need commercial
stabilizers and commercial equipment you
need to approach these recipes with a
commercial mind they are not like these
which are actually designed recipe wise
and instructionally for home ice cream
makers so folks down under don't give me
serious hate I'm just telling you how it
is I'm positive I'm 100% positive that
when I eventually get over to Australia
and go to gelato MSA then the I the ice
cream and gelato that they serve there
will be second to none I am positive of
that but as far as the recipe book goes
it's junk so there we go not a super
long video but out of all the recipe box
I'm going to recommend is the perfect
scoop by David leitz and hello my name
is ice cream By Dana cre these are the
two to get you on a better road to ice
cream obviously liking subscribing and
following along with me is going to
improve your ice cream no end but we all
need inspiration and we all need
information from various sources so that
is what this video is about if you have
an ice cream recipe book that you like
tell me in the comments what it is why
you like it and I will do my best to get
hold of it and have a look because I
love trying other people's ice cream
recipes and actually there's a couple of
bloggers that do really good ice cream
recipes you know and that's because they
follow the same path they created one
recipe that's really good and they they
use that to create others which is
absolutely fine because if you're if
you're like a baker and you do a broad
selection of
foods you you can't specialize in one
thing you have to be a bit Broad
shouldered and take on a bit of a jack
of all trades but if you hone down into
one specific thing like ice cream on
this channel we can Branch out and look
at other ways of doing things whether
that's low sugar low fat no eggs loads
of eggs no Dairy loads of dairy all
those kind of things high protein low
protein keto
plant-based literally the list could go
on forever thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe and I
will see you next time